Some already saw him as head of Germany's Social Democratic Party instead of Olaf Scholz.
But Defence Minister Boris Pistorius has quelled days of uncertainty about his Chancellor candidacy
pulling out of the parliamentary election race.
I have just informed our party and parliamentary group leaders that I will not be standing as
a candidate for the office of Chancellor.
This is my sovereign and personal decision.
He endorsed his competitor Olaf Scholz, who earlier this month saw the collapse of his three-way
coalition over differences about how to revive the economy.
I have repeatedly emphasised this in recent weeks, and I am making it very clear today.
In Olaf Scholz, we have an outstanding Chancellor.
For the SPD, the announcement comes as a wake-up call, as members within Olaf Scholz's own party
have raised doubts about his candidacy, with some politicians calling on Scholz to make way
for Pistorius, fearing that the already unpopular Chancellor would further put the party at a disadvantage.
National surveys show the SPD polling around 15 percent, well behind the Conservatives at 33
percent and behind the far right at 19 percent.
Olaf Scholz's entourage remains confident that the Chancellor could win, despite recent polls showing otherwise.
Only 21 percent of Germans see Olaf Scholz as a good candidate, compared to 60 percent who back Boris Pistorius.
The incumbent Chancellor's plummeting ratings have done little to stop Scholz, as the SPD leader
will run for a second term and is due to be officially nominated as a candidate on 11 January 2025.