President Putin has put the missile speculation to rest.
Russia's attack on the eastern Ukrainian city of Dnipro was carried out using what he called
a new intermediate-range ballistic missile, fired in response to Kiev's recent strikes using weaponry from Western allies.
Under combat conditions, a test of one of Russia's newest medium-range missile systems was also
carried out, in this case with a non-nuclear hypersonic ballistic missile.
Our missile engineers named it Oreshnik. The tests were successful.
One of the largest and most famous industrial complexes since Soviet times that still produces
weapons was destroyed in the Ukrainian city of Dnipro.
While unconfirmed reports from Ukraine suggested Russia had used an ICBM, an intercontinental
ballistic missile designed for long-distance nuclear strikes.
According to Putin, Oreshnik, Russian for hazelnut tree, is capable of Mach 10, going ten times the speed of sound.
And he warned that US and European air defence systems would be powerless to stop it.
Should more Oreshnik strikes be launched, he said Russia would issue advanced warnings to Ukrainian citizens, allowing for evacuations.
He also gave an ominous direct threat to the West, saying that the experimental missile could
also be used to attack any Ukrainian ally whose missiles are used to strike Russia.
The Pentagon confirmed that Moscow had launched an experimental intermediate-range ballistic
missile and that the US had had some forewarning.
In terms of notifications to the United States, the United States was pre-notified briefly before
the launch through nuclear risk reduction channels.
This was a new type of lethal capability that was employed on the battlefield, so that's certainly of concern to us.
Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky accused Putin of using Ukraine as a testing ground and
appealed to world leaders to react.