Welcome for this new tutorial. My name is Bruno Slaven. I've written an article
about augmented journalism practical implementation of semantic clustering,
multilingual transcription and some WordPress automation because I wanted to
apply the semantic clustering. So first of all we're going to go through a few
details so you can read the article if you want and you can grab on my GitHub
account all these elements. So I will try I would go first with Mistral OCR
then I will go on TrainingWhisper which is not exactly TrainingWhisper it's much
more about how to use how to use whisper on non not well documented language like
to go away from
French English and Spanish and take more rare language like for instance
I would say this way African language and stuff like that so anyway let's
start first first so I've got everything in command in all the you know the file
that has given on github and then I will do it manually in front of you so I'm
using for instance well this is maybe too much
I'm short-sighted so that's the reason why so right now we're going to go
through the first one so I have commented everything so you have a bunch
of so I'm going to use this environment you see it has changed I'm gone from
base to Mistral OCR I don't give you but you have the requirement everything that
you need
ok so this one for instance we're going to go this is source and he's going to
grab this little PDF and show me
for instance what is inside so you see this is fake PDF and it's just to show
you the ability of Mistral OCR to grab content for a very simple simple but
we will go with more complex PDF after and the fact that you need a Mistral
APK so for instance I'm not going to open my AMP because you will see my APK
but you need to have an APK fortunately this is this is a paid service but he
has very good
what I say
it's very interesting what I it's not what I say but what they have done is
like state of art understanding complex document natively multilingual and
multimodal which one thing that is very interesting for me and also you can
also self host organization dealing with highly sensitive and classify
information which is part of the sovereignty which is very important in a
way because if you're working on journalism of stuff that are really
radioactive you need to be sure that it's not going to share the content so
let's say you see whoops sorry I think I'm in the wrong yeah I am in the wrong
directory by the way I should update maybe this one okay that was a correct
one so let's do it and you see so he has given yes they can yes yes see one page
and then he's outputting the text meaning that you can output the text
text in whatever you want and let's say so that was you know i've given so i'm just presenting
few files so the three the four and the five i've already opened it because it's quicker to do the
tutorial but you can so also seize you with the thing that i've made so let's say the three the
four sorry that's another use case so right now i'm just gonna see if i'm in the correct place
yeah i'm still in the correct place so i'm just checking that the command that i've made are okay
the comment sorry and then so this one is going to do is going to take for instance a bigger one so
let's go to i think you have you can see a certain amount of of french and mostly french and then
english so let's stay this one i have to i've grabbed this one it's snowflake edition about
generative ai and lm and you would see you have i guess you have a certain amount of page which is
almost 44 and then you have the text and then you have the text and then you have the text and then
each of the one are going to be in the order of three and then you have the text and then you have
a lot of stuff which is very very complicated sometimes where you have three pages of text
and then you have to go to the four and the five and then you have the three pages and the four i guess and you have a lot of bunch of stuff like that anyway we gonna create so i'm
gonna take youtube three i think i made some taste and it should go right away so you see you have
youtube three youtube to youtube because i made some tests and this time it's going to grab everything
from this pdf so it's take a little bit of time and it should go yeah that's right so he has made
three
let's see that three and you see you have a bunch of stuff which is almost
the content it's correct as it is in English it's even better but you should
try also in Spanish in French and whatsoever if you need to do so but for
instance I want to and then you can retreat this information for instance I
don't need this image I just want to get rid of them so I'm gonna go through this
one and clean up you know making some operations which is I'm trying to find
some structured content from PDF and then I'm doing some post-production or
some post-treatment so for instance this one is gonna you're gonna grab
everything that looked like an image and he's gonna clean up the stuff so I would
say this is three and I would say three okay so that's he's gonna take the just
the document we have created and he's gonna clean up everything inside so
you can add some stuff some reg X or whatever so ever and clean up your
things so he has made the job you see it's pretty quick and then you see if
you compare you have this has disappeared because I was not needing a
such a thing and it's more clean and so you can detect some pattern inside the
text whatsoever and then I mean consolidate your content what's for for
any purpose like if you want to do a rag if you want to do some exploration
if you don't do whatever you want and it's a very interesting way of working
with different combination of document you have a lot of documentation right
here I just explored the basic the basic of
Mr. Ossier but you have a lot of possibility it's pretty well documented
except that you have to pay for it it's not so expensive but still you you if
you have to treat thousands of document yet it will cost a lot
so I will hand up this video so we're gonna go through the case to which is
training whisper which is not exactly training I should I should change the
text but at the at the beginning that was one of my ideas but I want to test
more different languages that's exactly what I'm saying right here in my queue
this is a multi language that is interest me and if you need I also have
some stuff about code switching okay but let's see it in the second video if you
like my work please subscribe to my channel and I will see you in the next video
don't forget to subscribe to my youtube channel for instance which is right here
and you can grab the content and read the article if needed okay see you bye
bye
you